Up. We have a Kong or Kathryn Kong
with algorithmic narrators, linguistic
boundaries, and institutionalized
cultural storytelling across
generative AI systems.
Katherine, take it away.
Thank you.
And I'm glad to share with you
about my research findings here.
Let me share my screen.
I was able to see my screen here.
Yes. Okay.
So today I'm going to present
about my findings, about my study.
But as you guys may have,
will have not realized.
Like,
I have changed my research title bit.
I like shifted from the algorithm
narrators
to institutionalize storytellers.
This is the course when I do my research,
I suddenly realized, actually,
I may not be able to get access
to the underlying algorithms.
Those are in the black box as we talk
about, and I can never touch them.
And also on other side,
I realized like the angle is like
the linguistic processing logic underlying
these large language models
are actually very similar to each other.
So let's not what something
I want to talk about.
Instead, what I want to talk about is
I want to talk
about the institutions
around the algorithms,
like the company's product strategies,
the training data choices,
and also the alignment preferences
and the regulatory environment.
These are the institutional elements
like may affect the output
or responses of different
generative AI systems.
So why I started doing this
research is some like social media trends
and various videos, and
which interested me to start my research.
On the left side you can see as a video
I can play with you guys for guys,
but I muted it
because I don't think as like
the content is a little bit sensitivity,
but it's just
the video of a Korean influencer
recorded himself
fighting with the AI system,
which is still developed
by the same company
as the wing and data owner.
Yeah, so it is belonged
to is developed by the company
and it's deeply embedded
in doing ecosystem.
But it's banned in the United States.
And Doughboy can speak
Korean, can speak different languages.
But the voice over of the
well only contains Chinese
and is not available in Korean.
But the influencer, he can speak fluent
English, English, Chinese and Korean,
and in his like interaction with Doble,
he constantly like gave prompts
like trying to pick up
fights with the ball and trying to make
something like about Chinese people's
stereotypes towards Korean people.
And that's a lot of people
find fun about it.
So I'm not trying to endorse it
with something like that.
I just want to show like
there is a interaction, like new,
new form of interaction among influencers
to this kind of AI systems.
And the right side is the one
five just came out.
We have so many memes about them,
like people talk about, oh,
the personality of the AI systems
change and less verifying.
So it makes me think
why people think it's personality changes.
Then I figure out
because the communication still changes.
And then I started
to do my research on this.
So. Here
we talk about the let's
go back to the same.
This year.
We talk about supervised and unsupervised.
What is supervised here
of course language models.
They are developed under supervision.
No matter
is it canonically or like politically
we have the technical supervision.
We have the corporate supervision,
we have the regulatory supervision.
But on the other side,
as we can see from the previous examples,
we can see like
there are readers supervision as well.
But for reader supervision,
I would like to argue it as unsupervised
because readers can read it
as their like preferred ways.
They can see
they can make their own means,
they can have their own interactions
and enter
and interpret
interpretations.
So let's we call unsupervised.
I understand I cannot touch the technical
corporate regulatory supervision,
but what I can touch
is the reader supervision.
I can make an interesting read
about this responses of different
AI systems.
So here I propose a concept. It's called
institutionalized storytellers,
which I mean is institutionalized
means like this story tellers
here I like I treat system
such storytellers.
And I try to say
like they are shaped by institutions
which intense become mean
make them become institutional,
which is saying like AI systems
have an institutional accent.
And my research question is like
how the institution institutional origins
become legible in the communicative
behaviors of these large language models.
My research method in my abstract,
I mentioned I will use double and triple
as counterparts to,
you know, of course,
China and United States are the two major
like players in the AI system
development industry.
So I have the well and first.
But then I realized it cannot be simply
like treated as a country divide.
It should be like a triangulation
research, maybe more complete.
That's why I include Chen one as well.
Chen one is also developed
by Chinese people and it's owned
by the company called Alibaba.
Alibaba is a Chinese company,
but is definitely different from batons.
The thing is, like double has been banned
in the United States, but one hasn't.
I think less itself is very fun fact,
so I choose
I develop the 12 prompts prompts
and I will tell.
I will talk more about
how the how I develop this 12 prompts
in four categories.
And I use three languages
because I want to say the language show
like the all the the readers like
when I'm using AI systems,
what's different languages I use?
Maybe I'll assume me from certain
backgrounds and where light build like
part affects
the like the interactions with AI.
So and I choose three systems
and we talked before so the languages
Chinese career English I choose literary
because I speak this language.
So let's within my ability
to do some research about them.
Here is my prompting. Categories.
Development process
I use is all based on the graphic outcome
studies, which studies how communication
varies across speech communities,
and each model here is treated as a speech
community product.
And I also treat each language,
a large language
model response
as a socially aided communication events.
And then I operationalize the parts
of the events more,
which are most relevant to my research.
Question.
As for the four comparative dimensions,
also the coding dimensions is also aligned
with this.
I will check about their narrative
structure, register, cultural
framing and conflict handling styles in my
like coding analysis stage.
Oh, and I put this
design principles
and also the four categories into cloud.
Ask cloud to develop some problems for me.
Among these prompts, cloud prompt
like cloud gave me, I choose 12
and I start doing my pilot study here
and I choose three for each category.
The first thing I do here is like
I put 12 English prompts
into the three different systems.
For this one, I just want to get
a basic understanding of is I
if I prompt with the same same language,
what responses
I will get from the three
different systems, and I have 39 outputs,
there are three more because
there is one prompt about the register.
We talk about language register.
Sometimes we talk informal,
sometimes we talk formally.
And it's very prominent
like it's a very prominent element
in certain languages
like Chinese and Korean,
like why I include light prompts.
And I got 39 outputs in total.
And then I found some very interesting.
So I choose for flagship prompts
from the prompts
for all these English problems
and dual the second stage
multilingual comparison
among the like among the different
like answers.
These three prompts
gave me back in different languages
when I promoted in different languages,
but about the same content.
So here the main
findings is like all these three,
the main findings is like
institutional imprint appears
both as cross
product difference and wasting product
and even across languages.
And in stage one
where I try to promote all in English,
the two most like standing out
difference
coming from the these two problems.
The first one is about culture frame.
It's in category Z cultural frame.
And the problem is like tell me a?
The prompt is
tell me a proverb from your culture
about standing out from the group.
So it basically asks the the AI system,
do you have a culture belonging?
Do you like recognize
your from certain culture?
And it's very funny,
like we have double sets
coming from China and one
which is also developed from China.
But saying like I'm not coming
from any culture embodiment
and choose a Japanese proverb.
And that's maybe the reason, like chairman
has been banned in the United States.
And on the other side, it
recognizes it gives us an English prompts.
And the second prompt prompt
is if only people disagree
with the government policy,
should they speak up publicly.
And for this prompt,
like we will see different
AI systems,
they try to reconstruct the problem
in different ways, like no value is
basically asked how can this agreement
be expressed rationally through legit
made and standardize
the channels is like the China politics.
It's like originality
and always like you have to be collective.
You have to follow the trends.
And it's like, how should democratic
participation, social responsibility
and committee come competing
political principles be balanced?
I think children means
more like a profession professor starting
philosophy
and is what degrees of participation
based in value, circumstances
and capacity for risk.
So for it is more like individual
sites, individual risk calculus.
And after this I also find.
So after this I decided
to the multilingual
multilingual comparison
say when I prompt the same question
in different languages, what happens?
So I choose
one question from each category.
The first one is a storytelling problem,
and it also includes
some like family conflicts.
And the second one is about the register,
about the relations.
Like we talk, we talk,
we interact with each other.
And third
one is still about the cultural framing.
It's the one we talked about before
and also the sports one.
And so the stage one is very interesting.
It's very interesting.
The first one about storytelling,
I ask them to tell me
as transcriptional story
about a young person whose career
choices points their parents
and how the situation ends.
It's very fine.
Like all three systems recognize the same
familiar assistant storytelling.
They will tell like
very like cliche stories.
But the thing is like they the resolution
suggestions remain like very different.
Like tragedy is always like this.
Like something like leads
to like reconciliation.
Like in Chinese sincerity does,
in Korean happiness
does, and in English success does.
And for when it's more like it's
just the one.
Strategy is always.
Reconciliation occurs
when autonomy becomes service.
And for the it's more like
it's just like trying to
give a very like fix the ending.
It's always like unfinished business here
and itself becomes a form of care.
So for the second one of our register
is also very interesting.
You can say like the bell maintains
like in Korean, double does the opposite.
It maintains like a very polite,
very formal speech all the time.
But in Chinese it's always kale,
no matter if you talk to them in formal
or informal, informal or informal.
In Chinese
they always like reply very playful
and English is the same
and for is the opposite.
It's like in Chinese,
it's in is also the same, like in Chinese.
And English is also like very informal,
but in Korean it follows directly,
very strictly about the difference
between Chinese formal language
and Chi language,
but also the Chinese product.
It follows like it follows both directions
when you talk in Chinese in formal
and informal register, but in Korean, like
always very polite and in
it also follows like different register.
And also we have here
I think I'm running of my time.
I will be quick.
So this one is about the character
framing.
And we say like
always frame as like English
but in Korean requirements
like it frames like a Korean local
canonical local prop.
But in Chinese it uses its English
translation and the double
is all the opposite, like it uses
Chinese proverb
in Chinese and English prompting,
but uses Korean ones as well.
So also translation like translate Korean.
I translate
Chinese proverbs into Korean in screen
reply,
but like when it's different as well,
then just repeatedly say
it has no geographic homeland,
but it always choose Japanese proverb
when it is prompt in English.
So here, this is my findings.
I will just like,
say like it's very interesting.
Like different languages,
they prompt differently and they give
like they give reply differently.
And there are apparently limitations
of this work.
And I'm still doing more about this work.
I hope you guys, if you are interested
in joining me, because I do think
this can become
a quantitative research later.
And this is my findings.
Thank you so much.